Bienen, Leigh B.; Papers apap312
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Reference Materials, 1872, 1935, 1951-2011, Undated; 5; 8.2 cubic ft.
  - David S. Baine, "Report to the New Jersey Supreme Court: Systemic Proportionality Review Project 2004-2005 Term", 2005 December 15 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - "The Death Penalty in New York", a report on public hearings by Assembly Committees, 2005 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - Mary E. Forsberg, "Money for Nothing? The Financial Cost of New Jersey's Death Penalty", 2005 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - Mary E. Forsberg, "Money for Nothing? The Financial Cost of New Jersey's Death Penalty", 2005 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - Indian Law Journal Symposium: Toward a Model Death Penalty Code: The Massachusetts Governor's Council Report, 2005 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - Texas - Procedure in Capital Cases, 2005 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - "A Matter of Life and Death: The Effect of Life - Without - Parole Statues on Capital Punishment, 2006 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - Susan Bandes, "Howard Law Journal - Loyalty to One's Convictions: The Prosecutor and Tunnel Vision", 2006 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - Joe Biden interview advertisement, 2006 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - Linda Bilmes and Joseph E. Stiglitz, "The Economic Costs of the Iraq War: An Appraisal Three Years after the Beginning of the Conflict", 2006 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 14)
  - Deborah W. Denno, "The Scientific Shortcomings of Roper v. Simmons", 2006 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 15)
  - James S. Liebman and Laurence C. Marshall, "Less is Better: Justice Stevens and the Narrowed Death Penalty", 2006 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 16)
  - Adam Liptak, "Citing Risk of Missteps, Judges Set Hurdles for Lethal Injection; The New York Times, 2006 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 17)
  - State Indigent Defense Commissions, 2006 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 18)
  - Atlanta journal - Constitution Death Penalty Series, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 19)
  - Atlanta Journal - Constitution Series on Proportionality (Bienen Cited), 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 20)
  - AVMA Guidelines on Euthanasia, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 21)
  - Frederic Block, "A Slow Death", The New York Times op-ed, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 22)
  - Capital Jury Project Publications Bibliography, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 24)
  - Tad friend, "Dean of Death Row", 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 25)
  - Brenda Goodman, "Georgia Murder Case's Cost Saps Public Defense System", 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 26)
  - David Heinzmann, "Lawyers seek Lineup Data: Lawsuit files in bid to rebut police study on new procedures", 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 27)
  - Illinois Violent Death Reporting System, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 28)
  - Adam Liptak, "Does Death Penalty Save Lives? A New Debate", 2007; 2008 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 29)
  - Justin F. Marceau, "Deference and Doubt: The Interaction of AEDPA" and Stephen I. Vladeck,"AEDPA, Saucier, and the Stronger Case for Rights - First Constitutional Adjudication", 2007; 2009; 2010 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 30)
  - New Jersey Death Penalty Study Commission Report, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 31)
  - New Jersey Death Penalty Study Commission Report, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 32)
  - New Jersey Death Penalty Study Commission Report, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 33)
  - New Jersey Death Penalty Study Commission Report (Russo dissent p.81), 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 34)
  - New Jersey Death Penalty Study Commission Report - Issue 7 (Alternatives), 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 35)
  - News Coverage of Costs of Brian Nichols case - State requests payment from Fulton County, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 36)
  - Raymond Paternoster, et. al., "An Empirical Analysis of Maryland's Death Sentencing System with Respect to the Influence of Race and Legal Jurisdiction", 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 37)
  - Racial Justice Act - congressional record and floor discussion 1988 - 1994, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 38)
  - Racial Justice Act - Federal bills introduced 1988 - 1994, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 39)
  - Sage Maidens of Cornell University, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 40)
  - Thomas P. Sullivan, "Efforts to Improve The Illinois Capital Punishment System: worth the cost?", 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 41)
  - Syllabus - Baze v. Rees, 2007 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 42)
  - With Senate Vote, New Jersey Nears Repeal of Death Penalty, 2007 December 11 (Box 7 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 43)
  - Baze v. Rees, 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Locke E. Bowman, "Lemonade out of Lemons: Can Wrongful Convictions Lead to Criminal Justice Reform?", 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - California Commission on the Fair Administration of Justice, ca. 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - California Commission on the Fair Administration of Justice, 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - California Commission on the Fair Administration of Justice (Ryan Commission), 2008; 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - Death Row U.S.A., 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - Death Row U.S.A.: A quarterly report by the Criminal Justice Project of the NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund Inc., 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - John J. Donohue III, "Capital Punishment in Connecticut, 1973 - 2007: A Comprehensive Evaluation from 4600 Murders to one Execution", 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - Erik Eckholm, "Citing Workload, Public Lawyers Reject New Cases", 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - The Justice System Journal, vol. 29, no. 3, 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - The Justice System Journal, vol. 29, no.3, 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - Thomas P. Sullivan, "Recording Federal Custodial Interviews", 2008 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - Article on Georgia inability to pay for defense in capital cases, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 14)
  - Philip J. Cook, "Potential Savings from Abolition of the Death Penalty in North Carolina", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 15)
  - Troy Anthony Davis, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 16)
  - Death Row U.S.A., 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 17)
  - Federal Death Penalty Online Resources, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 18)
  - "Getting it Right", Boston Bar Association Report, 2009; 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 19)
  - Gregg v. Georgia (1975) Syllabus, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 20)
  - Literature on Plea Bargaining and the Death Penalty, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 21)
  - Margery Malkin koosed, "Creighton Law Review - Performing Eyewitness Identification Law and Practices to Protect the Innocent", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 22)
  - New Mexico House Bill 2085 (abolishing the death penalty), 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 23)
  - New York v. Fernando Bermudez, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 24)
  - Northwestern Innocence Project Article, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 25)
  - "One in 31: The Long Reach of American Corrections", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 26)
  - Proffitt v. Florida (1975) Syllabus, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 27)
  - Bill Rankin, "State can't Afford to defend capital murder cases", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 28)
  - Regional Murder Rates 1996-2008, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 29)
  - Report of the Council to the Membership of the American Law Institute on the Matter of the Death Penalty, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 30)
  - Roberts v. Louisiana, Syllabus, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 31)
  - "Smart on Crime: Reconsidering the Death Penalty in a Time of Economic Crisis - National Poll of Police Chiefs Pats Capital Punishment at the Bottom of Law Enforcement Priorities", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 32)
  - Thomas P. Sullivan and Andrew W. Vail, "The Consequences of Law Enforcement Officials Failure to Record Custodial Interviews as Required by Law", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 33)
  - Annie Sweeney, "Chicago Homicides Drop", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 34)
  - Eric A. Tirschwell and Theodore Hertzberg, "Politics and Prosecution: A Historical Perspective on Shifting Federal Standards for Pursuing the Death Penalty in Non-Death Penalty States", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 35)
  - Rob Warden, "Reflections on Capital Punishment", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 36)
  - Rob Warden, "Reflections on Capital Punishment", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 37)
  - Carol J. Williams, "Death Penalty is considered a boon by some California Inmates", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 38)
  - Marcia J. Wilson, "The Application of the Death Penalty in New Mexico, July 1979 through December 2007: An Empirical Analysis", 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 39)
  - Woodson v. North Carolina (1975) Syllabus, 2009 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 40)
  - John H. Blume, "The Times they are A-Changin' (or are they?)", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 41)
  - Quintin Chatman, "The War against Capital Punishment", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 42)
  - Clippings, 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 43)
  - Crim Prof Blog, "Cleared and Pondering the Value of 27 Years", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 44)
  - Theodore Eisenberg and Sheri Lynn Johnson, "The Transformation of Capital Punishment", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 45)
  - Equal Justice Initiative, "Illegal Racial Discrimination in Jury Selection: A Continuing Legacy", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 46)
  - Adam M. Gershowitz, "Statewide Capital Punishment: The Case for Eliminating Countries' Role in the Death Penalty", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 47)
  - William Glaberson, "Reliving Horror in a Test for the Death Penalty", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 48)
  - Samuel R. Gross, "How the Death Penalty works: Empirical Studies of the Modern Capital Sentencing System" from 1998 Cornell Law Review Symposium, 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 49)
  - Illinois Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Quarterly Newsletter, 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 50)
  - Illinois is Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Annual Report, 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 51)
  - Kitchen v. Burge et. al., 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 52)
  - David J. Luban, "The Conscience of a Prosecutor", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 53)
  - Adam Liptak, "Stevens Settles Legal Mystery in Frank Essay, 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 54)
  - Juan A. Lozano, "DA claims Texas Judge has Death Penalty Bias", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 55)
  - Robert J. Martin, "Killing Capital Punishment in New Jersey: The First State in Modern History to Repeal it's Death Penalty Statute", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 56)
  - "Outlaw the Death Penalty to save lives and cash", Chicago Sun-Times, 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 57)
  - "Padilla v. Kentucky: The Right to counsel and the Collateral Consequences of Conviction", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 58)
  - Southern Center for Human Rights newsletter, 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 59)
  - Texas Judge declares death penalty unconstitutional, 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 60)
  - Mary Williams Walsh, "Eight States Have Shortchanged pensions, study finds", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 61)
  - Charles N. Wheeler III "Public Opinion Appears to Have Shifted in the Capital Punishment Debate", 2010 (Box 8 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 62)
  - John J. Donohue III, Capital Punishment in Connecticut, 1973 - 2007: A Comprehensive Evaluation from 4686 Murders to one Execution, 2011 (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 1)
  - Clippings, Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 2)
  - "Conversational Analysis Can Turn Tape Cases Around", Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 3)
  - Karen Ross Demers, "The Medicalization of the Death Penalty", Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 4)
  - "The Hidden Death Tax: The Secret Costs of Seeking Execution in California", Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 5)
  - Jury Questionnaire, Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 6)
  - Mental Retardation: Definition, Classification and Systems of Supports (excerpts), Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 7)
  - New Hampshire Attorney General, Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 8)
  - New Jersey v. Gwain Wynn, Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 9)
  - "Governor Quinn should empty death row", Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 10)
  - Mental Retardation, Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 11)
  - Juror Questionnaire, Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 12)
  - Nebraska v. Williams, Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 13)
  - United States v. James T. Murphy, Undated (Box 9 (5-Reference Materials), Folder 14)